window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "C_Programming - C_Programming — Slot 15 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "C_Programming — Slot 15",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>What is the result of the following program?<br><pre><code>    program side-effect (input, output);\n    var x, result: integer;\n    function f (var x:integer:integer;\n    begin\n        x:x+1;f:=x;\n    end\n    begin\n    x:=5;\n    result:=f(x)*f(x);\n    writeln(result);\n    end</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1998)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>5</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>25</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>36</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>42</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>36</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1685/gate1998-2-13\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>What value would the following function return for the input x=95?<br><pre><code> Function fun (x:integer):integer;\nBegin\n    If x &gt; 100 then fun = x- 10\n    Else fun = fun(fun (x+11))\nEnd;</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1998)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>89</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>90</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>91</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>92</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>91</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1684/gate1998-2-12\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>The conditional expansion facility of macro processor is provided to <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1997)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>test a condition during the execution of the expanded program</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>to expand certain model statements depending upon the value of a condition during the execution of the expanded program</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>to implement recursion</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>to expand certain model statements depending upon the value of a condition during the process of macro expansion</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>to expand certain model statements depending upon the value of a condition during the process of macro expansion</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2225/gate1997-1-9\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following macros can put a macro assembler into an infinite loop?<br>I.<pre><code>.MACRO M1, X\n.IF EQ, X   ;if X=0 then\nM1 X + 1\n.ENDC\n.IF NE, X   ;if X \\(\\neq\\) O then\n.WORD X  ;address (X) is stored here\n.ENDC\n.ENDM</code></pre> <br> II.<pre><code>.MACRO M2, X\n.IF EQ, X\nM2 X\n.ENDC\n.IF NE, X\n.WORD X + 1\n.ENDC\n.ENDM </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1996)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>II only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>both I and II</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>II only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2745/gate1996-2-16\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>A language with string manipulation facilities uses the following operations<br><pre><code>head(s): first character of a string\ntail(s): all but exclude the first character of a string</code></pre><pre><code> concat(s1, s2): s1s2</code></pre>\nFor the string \"acbc\" what will be the output of<pre><code>concat(head(s), head(tail(tail(s)))) </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>ac</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>bc</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>ab</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>cc</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>ab</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2621/gate1995-2-9\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>What is the value of X printed by the following program?<br><pre><code>program COMPUTE (input, output);\nvar X:integer;\nprocedure FIND (X:real);\n    begin\n        X:=sqrt(X);\n    end;\nbegin\n    X:=2\n    FIND(X);\n    writeln(X);\nend.\n </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Run time error</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>2</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2616/gate1995-2-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Assume that X and Y are non-zero positive integers. What does the following Pascal program segment do?<br><pre><code>while X &lt;&gt; Y do\nif  X &gt; Y then\n    X := X - Y\nelse\n    Y := Y - X;\nwrite(X);\n </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Computes the LCM of two numbers</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Divides the larger number by the smaller number</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Computes the GCD of two numbers</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Computes the GCD of two numbers</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2615/gate1995-2-3\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>What are x and y in the following macro definition?<br><pre><code>macro\tAdd x, y\n        Load y\n        Mul x\n        Store y\nend macro\t </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Variables</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Identifiers</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Actual parameters</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Formal parameters</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Formal parameters</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2598/gate1995-1-11\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>In the following Pascal program segment, what is the value of X after the execution of the program segment?<br><pre><code>X := -10; Y := 20;\nIf X &gt; Y then if X &lt; 0 then X := abs(X) else X := 2*X; </code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>10</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>-20</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>-10</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>-10</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2591/gate1995-1-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>In which of the following cases is it possible to obtain different results for call-by-reference and call-by-name parameter passing methods? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Passing a constant value as a parameter</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Passing the address of an array as a parameter</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Passing an array element as a parameter</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Passing an array</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Passing an array element as a parameter</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/305/gate1994-1-20\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>An unrestricted use of the \"goto\" statement is harmful because <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1994)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>it makes it more difficult to verify programs</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>it increases the running time of the programs</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>it increases the memory required for the programs</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>it results in the compiler generating longer machine code</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>it makes it more difficult to verify programs</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2442/gate1994-1-5\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>What does the following code do?<br><pre><code> var a, b: integer;\nbegin\n    a:=a+b;\n    b:=a-b;\n    a:=a-b;\nend;</code></pre> <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>exchanges a and b</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>doubles a and stores in b</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>doubles b and stores in a</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>leaves a and b unchanged</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>exchanges a and b</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2292/gate1993-7-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Refer to the PASCAL program shown below.<br><pre><code>Program PARAM (input, output);\nvar m, n : integer;\nprocedure P (var, x, y : integer);\nvar m : integer;\nbegin\nm : = 1;\nx : = y + 1\nend;\nprocedure Q (x:integer; vary : integer);\nbegin\nx:=y+1;\nend;\nbegin\nm:=0; P(m,m); write (m);\nn:=0; Q(n*1,n); write (n)\nend</code></pre> <br>What is the scope of m declared in the main program? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>PARAM, P, Q</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>PARAM, P</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>PARAM, Q</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>P, Q (e)</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>PARAM, P, Q</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B2D2Vl5_6vK1V0p0NnMydFMxWjQ/view\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Refer to the PASCAL program shown below.<br><pre><code>Program PARAM (input, output);\nvar m, n : integer;\nprocedure P (var, x, y : integer);\nvar m : integer;\nbegin\nm : = 1;\nx : = y + 1\nend;\nprocedure Q (x:integer; vary : integer);\nbegin\nx:=y+1;\nend;\nbegin\nm:=0; P(m,m); write (m);\nn:=0; Q(n*1,n); write (n)\nend</code></pre> <br>The value of n, output by the program PARAM is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>0, because n is the actual parameter corresponding to x in procedure Q.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>0, because n is the actual parameter to y in procedure Q.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1, because n is the actual parameter corresponding to x in procedure Q.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1, because n is the actual parameter corresponding to y in procedure Q.</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B2D2Vl5_6vK1V0p0NnMydFMxWjQ/view\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Refer to the PASCAL program shown below.<br><pre><code> Program PARAM (input, output);\nvar m, n : integer;\nprocedure P (var, x, y : integer);\nvar m : integer;\nbegin\nm : = 1;\nx : = y + 1\nend;\nprocedure Q (x:integer; vary : integer);\nbegin\nx:=y+1;\nend;\nbegin\nm:=0; P(m,m); write (m);\nn:=0; Q(n*1,n); write (n)\nend</code></pre> <br>The value of m, output by the program PARAM is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1993)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1, because m is a local variable in P</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>0, because m is the actual parameter that corresponds to the formal parameter in p</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>0, because both x and y are just reference to m, and y has the value 0</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1, because both x and y are just references to m which gets modified in procedure P</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>0, because m is the actual parameter that corresponds to the formal parameter in p</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2291/gate1993-7-1-2-3\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
